(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-14T01:42:04.998882",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ホロライブ格付けスペシャルー！
Hololive Kakuzuke Special!
本日はアイドル力の格付けということで
Today, we'll be ranking idol abilities,
超超一流のアイドルたちをお呼びしております！
so we've invited some super top-tier idols!
まずは本日誕生日の主役
First up is today's birthday star...
天音かなた様ー！
Amane Kanata-sama!
皆様、こんかなた！
Hello everyone, Konkanata!
ホロライブ4期生...
I'm from Hololive 4th Generation...
握力... んー... 50kgくらいある...
My grip strength... um... is around 50kg...
天音かなたです！
I'm Amane Kanata!
ぎゅっぎゅっと握りつぶさせて頂きたいと存じます！
I'd love to crush you all with a tight squeeze!
本日は一流アイドルを保ち続けるのが
Staying a top-tier idol today is my duty,
私めの使命だと思っておりますので、何卒よろしくお願い申し上げます！
so I count on your support!
握力ぎゅっぎゅって言ってる時点で
Mentioning her grip strength already makes me question
一流アイドルなのか疑問ではありますけれども...
whether she's really a top-tier idol, but...
はい！続いては、ときのそら様ー！
All right! Next up is Tokino Sora-sama!
はい！皆さんご機嫌ようですわ！
Yes! How do you do, everyone?
ときのそらです！
I'm Tokino Sora!
本日はこんな素敵な番組に来させて頂いて
I'm so happy to be invited
とても嬉しく思っています！
to such a wonderful show today!
一流アイドルのまま終われるように
I'll do my best to remain a top-tier idol until the end,
精一杯頑張っていきたいと思いますので、どうぞよろしくお願いします！
so please cheer for me!
こんそめ〜♪
Konsome~♪
可愛い〜！！
So cute~!!
えー、さらに豪華なゲストが続きます！
Next up, we have another gorgeous guest!
AZKi様ー！
AZKi-sama!
はい！皆さんこんあずき〜！
Yes! Hello everyone, Kon-AZKi~!
こんあずき～！
Kon-AZKi~!
今日は一流アイドルのままでいたいなと思っております！
Today, I want to remain a top-tier idol!
よろしくお願いしま～す！
Nice to meet you all!
そして最後のゲストはこの方！兎田ぺこらさんです！
And our final guest is this person! Usada Pekora-san!
はい！こんぺこでございますわ～！
Hi! Konpeko to you all~!
あれ？
Huh?
お黙りなさって
Quiet, please.
本日は一流アイドルとしてお呼ばれされました、兎田ぺこらでございます
Today I was invited as a top-tier idol, I am Usada Pekora.
王冠ギリギリ付いてる感じですね
Your crown is barely hanging on.
王冠の位置についてはちょっと... どうにかしてください
About the crown's position... Please do something!
私にも戸惑ってるんです！
I'm confused too!
今日は一流アイドルを保って...
Today, I'll maintain my top-tier idol status...
ニセ一流アイドル達もいらっしゃるみたいなんですけども
Though it seems there are also fake top-tier idols here...
ときのそら様に失礼なことを...
Saying something so rude to Tokino Sora-sama...
まあまあまあ...
Now, now, now...
一流、偽の方々も多いので
Since there are many fake ones here,
一流アイドルとしての風格を出していけたらなと思います。よろしくお願いしま～す！
I hope to showcase the dignity of a top-tier idol. Nice to meet you!
このメンバーで格付けを行っていきたいと思います！
We'll be doing the ranking challenge with these members!
皆さんちなみに自信のあるジャンルは？
By the way, does anyone have a genre they're confident in?
食べもの！はいはいはい！！
Food! Me, me, me!!
肉ううう！！
Meat!!!
ちょちょちょい！ひとりずつひとりずつ！
Hold on, hold on! One at a time, one at a time!
天音かなた様はどんなジャンルがお得意ですか？
Amane Kanata-sama, what genre are you good at?
お肉はとても大好きなので
I really love meat,
豚肉と牛肉の違いはすぐに分かります
so I can easily tell the difference between pork and beef!
誰でも分かります！
Anyone can tell!
ときのそら様はどんなジャンルがお得意ですか？
Tokino Sora-sama, what genre are you good at?
普段から楽器とかをやるので
Since I usually play instruments,
楽器系なら出来るかな？と思います！
I think I can do well with instrument-related topics!
AZKi様はどんなジャンルがお得意ですか？
AZKi-sama, what genre are you good at?
普段は歌を歌っているので
Since I usually sing songs,
音楽のジャンルにはきっと詳しいと思います！
I think I'm quite knowledgeable about music genres!
兎田ぺこら様はどのようなジャンルがお得意でしょうか？
Usada Pekora-sama, what genre are you good at?
私にも食べものがちょっと得意なのかなと思うんですけど
I think I'm pretty good with food too,
にんじん刺さってますからね、高級にんじん、普通のにんじんくらいは分かりますので
considering I have a carrot sticking out. I can tell apart high-class carrots from normal ones,
ぜひ「にんじん」来ていただけたらなと思います
so I really hope a "Carrot" category comes up.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
今回は全部で6問のジャンルに挑戦！
This time, you'll challenge a total of 6 genre questions!
気になる格付けはこちらとなっております
Here are the rankings for today:
「一流アイドル」「普通アイドル」「二流アイドル」「他人の空似」「映せない」
"Top Idol", "Regular Idol", "Second-Rate Idol", "Lookalike", and "Cannot Be Shown".
「映せない」！？
"Cannot Be Shown"?!
皆様一流アイドルなので、現在この扱いを破格にさせていただいておりますが
Since you are all top-tier idols, we are currently giving you special treatment, but...
二流や他人の空似ということであれば、相応の扱いをさせていただく...
if you become "Second-Rate" or "Lookalike", we will treat you accordingly...
2回言ったw
She said it twice! lol
わたし達は一流アイドルでございますから
We are top-tier idols after all,
このまま一流アイドルのままでいてくだされば何の問題もございません
so as long as we stay top-tier idols, there will be no issue at all.
承知いたしました。敬具。
Understood. Yours sincerely.
「敬具」って言っとけば良いと思ってるやついるなあ
Someone thinks saying "Yours sincerely" solves everything!
[天音かなた アイドル来歴]
[Amane Kanata - Idol Career History]
最初のジャンルはこちらです！
The first genre is this!
紅茶
Black Tea
アフタヌーンティーでございますね！毎日していらっしゃるでございます
Afternoon tea! You have it every day, right?
こちらがダージリンの紅茶なんですけれども...
This is Darjeeling black tea...
1つは30gおよそ5000円の高級紅茶
One is high-class tea worth about 5,000 yen per 30g!
もう1つはコンビニで売られている一般的な紅茶
The other is general black tea sold at convenience stores.
そもそも皆様、もちろん一流アイドルですから「ダージリン」とは何かご存知？
First of all, as top-tier idols, you all know what "Darjeeling" is, right?
ダージリン... 紅茶ですよね？
Darjeeling... is black tea, right?
紅茶ですねw
It's black tea! lol
アールグレイ...
Earl Grey...
ハッサム？
Hassam?
アッサム！
Assam!
本当に駄目ですね
You're really hopeless.
「ダージリン」と言いますのは世界三大銘茶となっておりまして
"Darjeeling" is known as one of the world's top three teas,
特有のフルーティーな香りが特徴となっております
featuring a distinctive fruity aroma.
引き締まった渋みとコクがあります
It has a crisp astringency and rich body.
実際にね比べてもらうものを... あつ...
We'll have you compare them... Ah...
一流の司会者ではない？
Are you really a top-tier host?
本日三流司会者？
A third-rate host today?
黙れ黙れ！！
Shut up, shut up!!
それでは早速ですがときのそら様から格付けに移りたいと思います！
Now then, let me start the rating with Tokino Sora-sama!
いってらっしゃいませ いってらっしゃい いってらっしゃい！
Have a safe trip! Off you go!
はい それでは そら先輩 目隠し...
Alright then, Sora-senpai is blindfolded...
ちなみに YAGOOモデルの目隠しとなっております
By the way, this is the YAGOO-model blindfold.
格付け さっそく始めていきたいと思います！
Let's get right into the rating challenge!
それではまず 1番の紅茶 ダージリンの紅茶を飲んでいただきたいと思います どうぞ！
First, we'd like you to drink tea number 1, the Darjeeling tea. Please go ahead!
今お手元に...あると思うので 飲んでみてください！
I think it's in front of you now, so please try drinking it!
はい！いただきます！
Thank you for the drink!
どうですか？
How is it?
先ほどのリモのちょっとね あの 紅茶の説明なんかを思い出していただいて...
Try to recall Lamy's explanation of the tea from earlier...
ん〜...ちょっと苦味があるかな？って感じでは...
Hmm... It feels like it has a bit of bitterness...
あるんですけど でもすごく美味しい紅茶だなと思います！
...is how it feels, but I think it's a very delicious tea!
はい ありがとうございます！それでは次 2番の紅茶 飲んでいただきたいと思います ちょっとお手元に...
Right, thank you very much! Next, we'd like you to drink tea number 2. Here in front of you...
はい どうぞ！
Yes, here you go!
いただきます！
Thank you for the drink!
いかがですか？
How is it?
ん！？ お！
Mm!? Oh!
全然違うけど... どっちもすごく美味しいですｗｗ
It's completely different, but... both are super delicious! haha
ま どっちもね とても美味しい紅茶ではあるものの...どちらの方が えー より良い...
Well, although both are very delicious teas... which one is, um, better...
はい 大丈夫です！でも なんとな～く分かった気がします！
Yes, I'm fine! But I feel like I kind of get it!
お！ありがとうございます！それでは 1番 2番 ちょっと決めていただきましょうか！
Oh! Thank you very much! Then, shall we have you decide on number 1 or 2?
ときのそら様 高級紅茶はどちらでしょうか！？
Tokino Sora-sama, which one is the high-end tea!?
はい！
Yes!
2番！
Number 2!
どっちもすごく美味しかったんですけど...
Both were really delicious, but...
あの こっちの方が近づけた時に とっても良い匂いがした気がしたので...
Um, when I brought this one closer, I felt like it had a really nice aroma...
それこそフルーティーって言ってたみたいに そう言うなんかフルーツの甘い匂いがした気がしたので！
Just like how you said it was fruity, I felt like it had that sweet fruit-like scent!
なるほど！ありがとうございます！ときのそら様！
I see! Thank you very much, Tokino Sora-sama!
当たってると思います！
I think I got it right!
はい！それではお部屋の方に移動をお願いいたします！
Alright! Then please move to the room!
はい！
Okay!
ドキドキする... よいしょ...
My heart is pounding... Up we go...
あぁー！どうしよう！ドキドキする！
Ahhh! What should I do! My heart is beating so fast!
はい 続きましてAZKi様の格付けに移ってまいりたいと思います！
Alright, next up, let's move on to AZKi-sama's rating challenge!
それではまず 1番の紅茶から飲んでいただきたいと思います！
First, we'd like you to drink tea number 1!
はい... 匂いを... あ でもすごいな...
Okay... The scent... Ah, but it's amazing...
いただきます！
Thank you for the drink!
う〜ん！お！なんかいつも飲むものより...
Mmm! Oh! Somehow, compared to what I usually drink...
すごい... コクがある感じ...
It's amazing... It feels very rich...
香りが... 違う 甘い香りがしました
The aroma... It's different, it had a sweet aroma.
甘い香りがしました では2番も飲んでいただきましょうか！
It had a sweet aroma. Then, shall we have you drink number 2 as well?
はい！
Okay!
はえ！？ え さっきの... さっきの方が香りがすごかったな...
Huh!? Eh, the previous one... The previous one had a much stronger aroma...
いただきます
Thank you for the drink.
あぁ～！なんか 2番の方が...
Ahhh! Somehow, number 2...
どうですか？なんかパッと分かった感じですか？
How is it? Did you figure it out right away?
の 飲み馴染みがあるというか 普段飲んでる味に近い...なと 思いました
F-Familiar to drink, or rather, close to the taste I usually drink... is what I thought.
ということは もう ではAZKi様の中では決定したということで！
Which means it's already decided in AZKi-sama's mind!
はい！決まりました！
Yes! I've decided!
なるほど！それでは決定していただきましょう！
I see! Then let's have you make your choice!
それではAZKi様 高級ダージリン紅茶は1番 2番どちらでしょうか！？
Then AZKi-sama, which one is the high-end Darjeeling tea, number 1 or number 2!?
1番です！
Number 1!
1番の方がすごい... 甘いフルーティーな香りがして...
Number 1 has an amazingly... sweet, fruity aroma...
味もなんか... やっぱりなんかちょっと奥行きがある...気がしました！！
And the taste too... as expected, felt like it had some depth... to it!!
なるほど！ありがとうございます！それではAZKi様 1番のお部屋に... どうぞ！
I see! Thank you very much! Then AZKi-sama, to room 1... Go ahead!
はい！ありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you very much!
え〜 そらちゃんいるよな... いるよな... いるよね！行きます
Ehh, Sora-chan is here, right... She is, right... She must be! Here I go.
はい！
Here I go!
待って... 誰も... いない てことは...
Wait... Nobody... is here. That means...
これは... え〜 どっちなんだ〜！？ え〜 怖い！どうしよう！そらちゃ～ん！！
This is... Eh, which one is it~!? Eh, scary! What should I do! Sora-chan~!!
あずきち〜！
AZKichi~!
甘い匂いこっちの方がしたんだ〜
It smelled sweeter on this side~
本当！？ え〜甘い匂い... え〜どうしよう...
Really!? Eh~ sweet aroma... Eh~ what should I do...
はい！それでは続きまして かなた様の格付けを行ってまいります！
Alright! Next up, we will conduct Kanata-sama's rating challenge!
それでは1番のダージリンの紅茶から どうぞお飲みください！
Then, please go ahead and drink Darjeeling tea number 1!
ありがとうございます...
Thank you very much...
どうですか？
How is it?
なんか... 桑の葉みたいな匂いがします。
It smells kind of like mulberry leaves.
いただきます。
I will have a taste.
なるほど。どうぞ召し上がってください。
I see. Please go ahead and try it.
おっ、渋いねぇ...
Oh, it's astringent...
あー、なるほど。渋みがあると。
Ah, I see. It has a bit of astringency.
あー！なんかもうわかりました！
Ah! I already get it now!
まだ2番飲んでないですよ？
You haven't tried Number 2 yet, you know?
一応、じゃあ2番飲んで... まぁもう分かったけどね。
Well, I'll try Number 2... even though I already get it.
はい、では2番も飲んでみてください。
Yes, please give Number 2 a try as well.
匂い...
The scent...
いかがでしょうか？
How is it?
なんか2番の方が非常に香りが遠いですね。
Number 2 has a much more distant aroma.
心の距離感じる感じがする。
It feels like there's an emotional distance.
心の距離を感じますか？2番との紅茶。
Do you feel emotional distance with tea Number 2?
では、ちょっと2番いただきます。
Well then, I'll take a sip of Number 2.
え？
Huh?
なんて... どうしま... どうしました、かなた様？
What... What happened, Kanata-sama?
やべ... え？
Shoot... huh?
もう一度1番飲むことも可能ですけれども。
You can drink Number 1 again if you'd like.
じゃあ、もう一度1番を... すみません、いただきます。
Then, I'll try Number 1 again... Sorry, down the hatch.
はい。なるほど、決まりましたか？
Yes. I see, have you decided?
はい！完全にわかりました！
Yes! I completely get it now!
あ、なるほど。それではかなた様に1番2番、あげていただきましょう。
Ah, I see. Then let's have Kanata-sama hold up Number 1 or Number 2.
高級ダージリン紅茶は1番、2番、どちらでしょうか？
Which one is the expensive Darjeeling tea, Number 1 or Number 2?
ズバリ、1番！
Directly, Number 1!
おっ、1番ということで、こちらはどのような理由で？
Oh, choosing Number 1. What is your reason for this?
そうですね、あの、深みがまずありまして、
Well, you see, first of all, it has depth,
あの、舌の上に乗せた瞬間に広がっていく紅茶の香り、
the moment it touches your tongue, the tea's aroma spreads,
そして、明らかにあんまり「これは飲んだことないな」って感じの味がしました。
and it clearly had a taste like "I've never tasted this before."
「こりゃあ高ぇだろお！」と思った次第でございます。
"This must be expensive!" is what I thought.
自信あります！！
I have full confidence!!
ありがとうございます。それでは1番のお部屋に行ってください。
Thank you very much. Then please proceed to Room Number 1.
いや、多分間違ってないと思うんですよね。
Nah, I really don't think I'm wrong.
大丈夫だと思う... 2人いると思う。
I think it's fine... I think there are two people inside.
いきます！いち！
Here I go! One!
キャー！
Kyaaa!
待って！かなたそ来た！ / あー！よかったー！
Wait! Kanata-so came! / Ah! Thank goodness!
そら先輩は？？
Where is Sora-senpai??
こっちにいるさぁ〜！
I'm over here~!
そら先輩！？
Sora-senpai!?
そら先輩... どっ、え？どうして？
Sora-senpai... Wha-, huh? How come?
なんかいい匂いしたよね！
It smelled so good, right!
なんかすごい良い匂いがして、あんま普段飲まない味がしたから、
It had a really nice aroma and tasted like something I don't usually drink,
「高ぇのかな？」って...
so I thought, "Is this the expensive one?"
2の方がすっごい匂いしたんだよなぁ...
Number 2 had such a strong aroma though...
マジすか？
Seriously?
え、どっちかが間違ってるのか...
Eh, so one of us is wrong...
はい、それではぺこら様、高級ダージリン紅茶、どちらか当てていただきたいと思います。
Now then, Pekora-sama, we would like you to guess which one is the high-grade Darjeeling tea.
それでは1番のコップの紅茶から飲んでいただきたいと思います。
First, please taste the tea from cup Number 1.
いただきます。香りからね。
I shall partake. Starting with the scent.
そうですね、香りは大事ですね。
Indeed, the aroma is very important.
あ、嗅いだことあるわ、これ。
Oh, I've smelled this before.
うんうんうん、よく、噂に聞くと、なんか「ダージリンの国のお姫様」とか何とか...
Yeah yeah yeah, I often hear rumors about "the princess of the Darjeeling country" or something...
そういうことでございます。
That is correct.
自称ですよね？
That's self-proclaimed, right?
自称じゃないですよ。これ他称ですからね。
It's not self-proclaimed. It's what others call me.
あ、他称ですか笑
Ah, so others call you that! haha
ああなるほど、あ、でも、うん、あーなるほどね。この、このあれね、ダージリンね。
Ah I see, ah but, yeah, ah I get it. This... this Darjeeling, right.
おかゆ、じゃあ、いただきます。
Well then, I shall drink it.
あ、はい、飲んでみてください。
Ah, yes, please go ahead and taste it.
う〜ん。苦みが思った以上に... あ、なるほど。美味解でございます。
Mmm. The bitterness is more than I expected... Ah, I see. Delicious.
はい、ありがとうございます。それでは次に2番の紅茶を飲んでいただきたいと思います。
Thank you very much. Next, please taste tea Number 2.
いただきます。じゃあまず匂いからね。
I shall partake. First from the scent.
お、え？ん？匂いしないよ、これ。
Oh, huh? Hm? This doesn't have any smell.
いやいやいや... え、これ匂いしないよ？入ってる？
No no no... Eh, this doesn't smell like anything? Is there tea in here?
え、ぺこら様、大丈夫ですか？鼻炎とか、そういった...
Eh, Pekora-sama, are you okay? Do you have nasal inflammation or something...
私、鼻炎なんですか！？
Do I have nasal inflammation!?
鼻炎持ってる...
Having nasal inflammation...
え、でもさっきのはすごい香りが、あ、戻ってきたかも。
Eh, but the previous one had such a strong aroma... Ah, maybe it came back.
でも、これ、匂い無いのでちょっといただきたいと思います。いただきます。
Well, since this has no smell, I'll go ahead and try tasting it. Down the hatch.
はい、わかりました！
Yes, I got it!
おっ！流石ですね！もう分かりました！
Oh! As expected! You already get it!
それではちょっと1番、2番、決めていただきましょう！
Well then, please select either Number 1 or Number 2!
高級ダージリン紅茶は1番、2番、どちらでしょうか？
Which one is the expensive Darjeeling tea, Number 1 or Number 2?
はい！私が飲んだ高級ダージリンは... ドゥルルルル... 1番！
Yes! The high-grade Darjeeling that I drank was... Drumroll... Number 1!
おー！1番ということで、こちらはどのような理由で1番になさったんでしょうか？
Oh! Choosing Number 1. What reason led you to select Number 1?
えーっと、まず香りが、1番がすごい香ってきたぺこなんですね。
Well, first of all, the aroma of Number 1 was super strong, peko.
なるほど。
I see.
そして、飲んだ時に、苦味、渋み、とてつもなく強烈でございました！
And when I drank it, the bitterness and astringency were ridiculously intense!
あんまりなんか褒めてるように聞こえないんですよ、大丈夫ですか？
That doesn't really sound like praise, are you sure about that?
いやいや、それに比べて2番！香りは薄い！けど飲みやすい！コンビニで売られているような...
No no! Compared to that, Number 2! The aroma is weak! But easy to drink! Like something sold in a convenience store...
な...
I...
ダージリン
Darjeeling.
なるほど
I see.
私としては思いましたぺこですね。な、なので
That's how I felt, peko. S-So...
1番！高級ですわ！
Number 1! It's high class!
はい、ありがとうございます
Alright, thank you very much.
それでは1番のお部屋に向かってください
Then please head to Room 1.
じゃ、行ってきまーす！
Well, I'm off!
誰かしら居ろ... 頼む
Hope someone's in there... Please...
誰かいてくれ... 行きます！
Please someone be in there... Here I go!
こんにちはー！誰か...
Hello! Anyone...
あれ...？ 待って
Wait...? Hold on.
そう、そうなんだよ！
Yeah, yeah, that's right!
あれ？ そら先輩だけが...
Wait? Only Sora-senpai is...
そら先輩？ そらちゃん？
Sora-senpai? Sora-chan?
はーい！
Yeees!
うっそー！これ
No way! This...
嘘でしょこれ！
You've got to be kidding!
いや、でも3人いるから...
Wait, but since there are three of us...
私も分かんなかったから大丈夫！
I couldn't tell either, so it's okay!
そら先輩が向こうにいるだけで不安になる...
Just having Sora-senpai over there makes me anxious...
間違ってる可能性が高くなったかもしれない
The chances that we're wrong might have just gone up...
祈るしかないね
We can only pray...
うわ、マジで怖ぇぇぇ！
Woah, seriously scaryyy!
結果発表
[Result Announcement]
さあ、それでは正解の扉を開けていきたいと思います！
Now then, let me open the door to the correct answer!
こい！こい！
Come on! Come on!
えいっ！
Hyah!
あれ？ あれっ！？
Wait? Huh!?
やったーー！！
We did it!!
みなさん！一流アイドルですから...！
Everyone! We're first-class idols after all...!
一流アイドルでございます！！
We are first-class idols!!
よかった... でもちょっと悔しい... ドキドキした！
I'm glad... But a bit frustrated... That was nerve-wracking!
ときのおそら 1 RANK DOWN
[Tokino Sora: 1 RANK DOWN]
別世界
Another World
愛してくれ 僕のことを
Love me, love everything about me
どうか邪魔などしないでから
So please, don't get in my way
消せない写真と目合わせて
Locking eyes with photos I can't erase
嘆いてくれ 僕のことを
Grieve for me
あなたには届かないけど
Though it won't ever reach you
酷く焦がれる恋をしてた
I was head over heels in love
混ざることない指 息を止める
Fingers that never intertwine, holding my breath
天音かなた 作詞作曲『別世界』
'Another World', written and composed by Amane Kanata.
はい！ということでー
Alright! So then—
結果的には『普通アイドル』に、そらちゃんがなってしまったということですね
As a result, Sora-chan has dropped to 'Ordinary Idol'.
椅子のほうもちょっとランクが下がりまして、パイプ椅子みたいなね...
Her chair rank also went down to a metal folding chair...
ポンポンポン...
Tap tap tap...
そらちゃん、どうですか？
Sora-chan, how do you feel?
自分が好きな味の方を個人的に選んじゃった
I just personally picked the flavor that I preferred.
庶民的な感じで良いのかな？って思いました！
I thought maybe a relatable vibe would be fine!
なるほどー！
I see!
これ以上ランクが下がってしまいますと『二流アイドル』になってしまいますのでご注意ください
If your rank drops any further, you'll become a 'Second-rate Idol', so please be careful.
がんばりま〜す！！
I'll do my best~~!!
それではですね、次のジャンルに行きたいと思います
Well then, let's move on to the next genre.
『高級機材』でございます！
It's 'High-end Equipment'!
こちら、高い方の機材が市場価格...
Here, the more expensive equipment has a market price of...
80万円となっております！
...800,000 yen!
たっつかー！！ マイク！？
So expensive!! A mic!?
そして、もうひとつのマイクが市場価格3万円のマイクとなっております
And the other microphone has a market price of 30,000 yen.
3万も十分やん！
30,000 yen is plenty!
こちらですね、私が僭越ながら自己紹介ボイスを録らせていただきましたので...
For this test, I humbly recorded a self-introduction voice clip...
そちらで皆様にご判断いただきたいと...
So I'd like you all to judge based on that...
そういうことなんだー！
Ah, so that's how it works!
機材に自信があるよと、そらちゃんとAZKi様がおっしゃっておりましたけれども、今回自信のほどはいかがでしょうか？
Sora-chan and AZKi-sama mentioned earlier that you're confident with equipment, but how confident are you this time?
ラミィちゃんに合ったマイクかどうかみたいなところもあったりするので... でも高いマイクを当てたいと思います
It might depend on whether the mic suits Lamy-chan's voice... But I want to pick the expensive mic.
金額差が77万円ですからね！
The price difference is 770,000 yen, after all!
マイクの質とかはあんまり分からないんですけど、機材を見るのは好き！
I don't really know much about mic quality, but I like looking at equipment!
だから当てられたら嬉しいなって気持ちではあります
So I'd be happy if I get it right.
ちょっと予防線張ってませんか？
Aren't you setting up an excuse?
そりゃ張るよね！！ さっきのダージリンのダメージがちょっとある
Of course I am!! I took a bit of damage from that Darjeeling tea earlier.
それでは... そらちゃん！
Well then... Sora-chan!
ここ外してしまうと
If I get this wrong...
二流アイドルの…
I'll become a second-rate idol...
「そら」になってしまいますので
named "Sora"...
「そら」って呼んでくれるの？
"Will you call me 'Sora'?"
喜ばないでください！助けてください！
Don't be happy! Please help me!
それではまずね 1番の音声流していきます 1番お願いします
Now then, let's play audio sample #1 first. Number 1, please.
ホロライブ5期生の雪花ラミィです どちらが高級マイクか分かるかな？
I'm Yukihana Lamy from Hololive 5th Gen. Can you tell which one is the high-end mic?
続いて2番 流してください
Next, please play audio #2.
ホロライブ5期生の雪花ラミィです どちらが高級マイクか分かるかな？
I'm Yukihana Lamy from Hololive 5th Gen. Can you tell which one is the high-end mic?
もう一回聴くのって可能ですか？
Is it possible to listen to them one more time?
それではそらちゃん 高級マイク 1番の音声か2番の音声 どちらでしょうか？
Now then, Sora-chan, which audio was the high-end mic, #1 or #2?
こっち！2番！
This one! Number 2!
ということで 2番という理由は何でしょうか？
So, what is your reason for choosing number 2?
2番の方が…なんかふわっとして聴こえたというか…
Number 2... sounded a bit softer to me, or rather...
私自身は強い音が好きなので
Personally, I like punchier sounds,
1番が好きなんですけど…
so I preferred #1, but...
一般的に聴き心地が良いのは2番なのかな？と思って
I thought #2 might be generally more pleasant to listen to,
2番にしました
so I chose #2.
なるほど ということで2番
I see. So, number 2.
それでは2番のお部屋にお願いします
Well then, please head to room #2.
ドキドキ…毎回ドキドキしてます！
My heart is pounding... I get nervous every time!
一人目だから誰もいるわけないのに！
I'm the first one, so there's no way anyone is in here!
はい それではAZKi様 まず1番の音声からどうぞ！
Yes, now then, AZKi-sama, let's start with audio #1, please!
ホロライブ5期生の雪花ラミィです どちらが高級マイクか分かるかな？
I'm Yukihana Lamy from Hololive 5th Gen. Can you tell which one is the high-end mic?
それでは続きまして 2番の音声お願いします
Moving on, please play audio #2.
ホロライブ5期生の雪花ラミィです どちらが高級マイクか分かるかな？
I'm Yukihana Lamy from Hololive 5th Gen. Can you tell which one is the high-end mic?
いかがでしょうか？ これ難しい！
How was it? — This is tough!
もう一度聴くことも可能ですよ？
It's possible to listen again, you know.
さあ AZKi様 いかがでしょうか？ これ難しい…どちらんだろう…
Now then, AZKi-sama, how was it? — This is difficult... Which one is it...?
高級マイク 1番か2番 どちらでしょうか？
High-end mic, is it #1 or #2?
2番！2番！
Number 2! Number 2!
ということで こちらはどのような理由で2番に…？
And what is your reason for picking #2...?
いや 結構高いマイクって
Well, high-end microphones...
結構周りの音とかも割と拾いやすい
tend to pick up subtle ambient sound easily,
繊細な音とラミィちゃんの高音域が結構録れていた感じがして
and it felt like delicate sounds and Lamy-chan's high range were captured well.
スタジオで録るなら2番…なんかちょっと特徴があったので2番にしました
If recording in a studio, #2... It had distinct characteristics, so I went with #2.
なるほど 説明がとても「っぽい」感じですね
I see, your explanation sounds very professional!
これで外してたら恥ずかしいですねｗ
If I got this wrong, it'd be embarrassing, haha.
今度はそらちゃん居てくれ！居てくれ！
Please be there this time, Sora-chan! Please be there!
2番…そらちゃ～ん！！ あずきち～！！
Number 2... Sora-cha~n!! — Azukichi~!!
今度はひとりじゃないよ～！よかった～！！
I'm not alone this time~! Thank goodness~!!
はい それではかなた様！
Yes, now then, Kanata-sama!
ご自身でMIXなどもされてますので きっと分かりますよね？
Since you do audio mixing yourself, you'll surely know, right?
もちろんでございます！
Of course I do!
ということで 1番の音声から聴いていただきましょう！
So let's listen to audio #1 first!
ホロライブ5期生の雪花ラミィです どちらが高級マイクか分かるかな？
I'm Yukihana Lamy from Hololive 5th Gen. Can you tell which one is the high-end mic?
いかがでしょうか？ 決めました！
How was it? — I've decided!
早いですね！高級マイクは1番もしくは2番 どちらでしょうか？
That was fast! Is the high-end mic #1 or #2?
1番！ 1番ということで こちらはどうしてでしょうか？
Number 1! — Number 1, and why is that?
1番の方が ラミィの声に対してなんですけど
For #1, regarding Lamy's voice,
フラットに良く聴こえたなという印象がありまして
it sounded flat and clear to me.
ちなみに2番の方はですね ラミィの声だと…なんですけど
By the way, for #2, with Lamy's voice...
Highの音が「カキーン」って感じがして 非常に耳障りが良く
The high end felt sharp and bright, very pleasant to listen to,
高いマイクってMIXのイコライザーの必要がない いじる必要がないくらい…
and high-end mics are so good that you barely need to touch the EQ in mixing...
さすがMIXをされていらっしゃるかなた様だからこそのご意見ですね！
As expected from Kanata-sama who does her own mixing!
1番はほぼほぼいじらずに使えるなというイメージがあったので こっちです！
#1 felt like it could be used almost untouched, so it's this one!
これは自信ありですか！？ あります！
Are you confident in this!? — I am!
間違えられません！間違えたらおかしいですから こんなの！！
I can't be wrong! It'd be crazy if I got this wrong!!
こんなのお！！
No way!!
それでは1番のお部屋にお願いいたします！
Please head to Room 1!
はーい！いるよね？やべっ超不安！
Okay! Someone's in here, right? Man, I'm super anxious!
おねがいします！いてくれーー！
Please, be in here!
なんでぇ？なんで誰もいないの？
Why? Why is nobody here?
かなた〜ん！
Kanata-n!
なんでー！
Why?!
わあぁもう無理だっ！
Waaah, I can't take this anymore!
はい！それでは噂によると機材の国のお姫様、兎田ぺこら様...
Alright then, rumor has it... Usada Pekora-sama, Princess of the Kingdom of Equipment...
は〜いこんにちは！機材の国からやって参りましたぺこ〜！
Hi, hello! I'm here from the Kingdom of Equipment, peko!
それでは1番の音声、お願いいたします！
Alright then, please play the audio for number 1!
ホロライブ5期生の雪花ラミィです！
I'm Yukihana Lamy from Hololive 5th Gen!
どっちが高級マイクか分かるかな〜？
Can you tell which one is the high-end mic~?
耳はそっちなんですね？
Wait, your ears are over there?
ぺこら様... こ、こういう感じで...w
Pekora-sama... L-Like this... lol
ホロライブ5期生の雪花ラミィです！
I'm Yukihana Lamy from Hololive 5th Gen!
どっちが高級マイクか分かるかな〜？
Can you tell which one is the high-end mic~?
え？さあ、どうでしょうか、ぺこら様？
Huh? Well, what do you think, Pekora-sama?
もう一度聴かせてください。
Please let me listen to it one more time.
楽勝でした！
That was easy!
さすが機材の国のお姫様ということで。それでは札を上げていただこうと思います！
As expected of the Princess of Equipment. Now, please raise your paddle!
80万円のマイクを使った音声は...
The audio recorded using the 800,000 yen mic is...
2番！
Number 2!
2番ということで。こちら理由は？
So, number 2. And your reason is?
ラミィちゃんの声がすっとね、脳内に入ってくる感じがして...
Lamy-chan's voice just smoothly entered right into my brain!
まあ高い女は80万のマイクが似合うよなぁ！
A high-class woman fits an 800,000 yen mic!
まあ3万円のマイクでもね、十分高いマイクなんですけれども...
Even a 30,000 yen mic is quite expensive, but...
いや！雪花ラミィは80万円のマイクが似合うんだよ！
No! Yukihana Lamy deserves an 800,000 yen mic!
ありがとうございます。これで間違えたらちょっとラミィにもダメージが入るってことですね。
Thank you. If you get this wrong, Lamy will take damage too.
頼む... 居てくれ、誰か居てくれ...
Please... Someone be in here, please be in here...
2番マイクか。お願い、誰かしらいてくれ！
Number 2 mic, huh? Please, anyone! Be in here!
き、きたきたきたきた！
She came, she came, she came!
安心のメンツですわぁ！
That's a comforting lineup right there!
聞こえてるか〜？かなた〜ん！
Can you hear us~? Kanata-n!
だいじょぶぺこか〜？w
Are you okay, peko~?
こっちは3人で仲良く〜
Over here we have three people getting along nicely~
うそでしょ...
No way...
ぺこ〜ら先輩が行ったことにより、少し二人は不安になってるはず...
Since Pekora-senpai chose this room, the two must be feeling a bit uneasy...
おかしいぺこだろぉ！
That doesn't make sense, peko!!
結果発表
Results Announcement
ラミィさん！ラミィさん2番にお願いします！ラミィ様ー！
Lamy-san! Lamy-san, please come to Room 2! Lamy-san!
それでは... 1番と2番...
Now then... Room 1 and Room 2.
お願い！ラミィさんは... 2番！2番！
Please! Lamy-san! Room 2!
えぇ！？
What?!
やったーー！！
Yay!!
やった！やっぱり80万円のマイクがあっち...
Yay! As expected, the 800,000 yen mic was over there...
音に関してマスター、プロということで！
When it comes to sound, she's a complete pro!
聴いたのならばねぇ〜
If she listens to it, right~?
あああああああ！
AAAAAAAH!
間違えられません！
There's no way I can get it wrong!
間違えたらおかしいですからこんなの！
It'd be weird if I got it wrong!
間違えた人の部屋
[Room of the person who got it wrong]
天音かなた 1ランクDOWN
Amane Kanata: Down 1 Rank!
天音かなたメンバーシップ、皆様加入していただいておりますでしょうか？
Amane Kanata membership wall paper distribution in progress! Have you all joined yet?
こちらでは毎月、超超美麗なイラストの壁紙が配布されております！
Here, super beautiful wallpapers of illustrations are distributed every month!
そして前回行いました、プチ世界というライブのアンコールライブなども開催しました！
And we also held an encore live stream for the "Petitesail" live performance!
毎月ね、3日から4日は必ずメンバーシップの配信をしておりますので！よろしければメンバーに...
Every month, from the 3rd to 4th, I definitely stream for members, so please join!
はい、それでは高級マイクを当てられなかった、かなたちゃん...
Now then, Kanata-chan who couldn't guess the high-end mic...
ハイ！
Yes!
普通アイドルのかなたちゃん。
"Average Idol" Kanata-chan.
「普通アイドル」のかなたです...
I am Kanata, the "Average Idol"...
AZKi様、ぺこら様、一流アイドルを保ってらっしゃるということで！
AZKi-sama and Pekora-sama are maintaining their First-Class Idol status!
どうも〜！どうも〜！
Hello~! Hello~!
このままね、保っていただければと思います。
I hope you can maintain it for the rest of the game as well.
次のジャンルはこちら！
The next category is this!
ジャンル3、にんじんジュースでございます！
Category 3: Carrot Juice!
ああ〜もう…
Agh, come on...
全然違うわよ！？
They're completely different!?
え、入ってる材料同じなんですよね？
Wait, the ingredients are the same, right?
んフッ…
*chuckle*
今一瞬何か吹き出しかけましたけれども
I almost burst out laughing just now, but...
一時的にんじんジュースにハマってたことがあって
I used to be really into carrot juice for a while,
間違えられないですよ？
so I can't possibly get this wrong!
申し訳ないけどｗｗ
I'm sorry, but...
これ外す奴ヤバイぞ！！マジで！！
anyone who misses this is crazy! Seriously!
今回全問正解一番多い気がする！え、もう味違うもんこれ！
I feel like this question will have the most correct answers! The taste is totally different!
しまった〜！
Oh no~!
ウホッホッホッホッホッホ！！ソラセンパイ！！
Sora-senpai!!
誰も居らん！マジか！マズい！えぇ！？
Nobody's here! Seriously!? This is bad! What!?
居てくれ〜！
Please be someone in here~!
一流がひとりになると…
When an "A-Lister" is all alone...
結果発表
[Result Announcement]
どっちにしようかな？
Which room shall I choose?
お願いー！
Please~!
じゃ〜ん！
Ta-da!
えーっと、にんじんジュースにハマっていらっしゃった、AZKiちゃん！
Umm, AZKi-chan, who was so into carrot juice!
はい、えー「普通アイドル」になってしまいましたね〜
Yes, well, you've dropped down to "Ordinary Idol" now~
これは不覚…！
What a blunder...!
理由を、そう、ぜひぜひ聞きたいですね！
I'd really love to hear your reasoning!
なんかその、にんじん100％のなんか、甘いりんご…りんごじゃない、にんじんジュースを…
Well, like, a 100% carrot juice that's sweet like apple... not apple, carrot juice...
あれ？りんごって言ってますよ！
Wait, did she just say apple?
こんにちわぁ！一流アイドルのぺこら様が！
Hello~! The A-List Idol Pekora-sama is here!
やはり私、最初からこの3人がニセ一流アイドルだってことは見抜いておりましたので…
As expected, I saw right through these three being fake A-List idols from the start...
さすがでございます！！
As expected of you!!
やっぱりこうなるのは当たり前なのかなっと！
So I guess this outcome was only natural!
偶然ですよ！
It was pure coincidence!
それではですね、次のジャンル行きたいと思います！
Alright then, let's move on to the next category!
次のジャンルはこちら！
The next category is this!
日本酒でございます！
It is "Japanese Sake"!
まずひとつは、もちろん…
First up, of course, is...
大吟醸 雪夜月でございます！
the Daiginjo Yukiyozuki!
そしてもうひとつは、コンビニで売られている日本酒となっております！
And the other one is a Japanese sake sold at convenience stores!
皆様ね、「雪夜月」製作者の私の前で、もちろん当ててくださる…
Everyone, in front of me, the creator of "Yukiyozuki", you will of course guess correctly...
え、飲んだことあります？
Wait, have you drunk it before?
あ、あります…
Ah, I have...
ないです！すいません！
No, I haven't! Sorry!
まぁ、じゃあ、飲んだことあるかなたちゃんはね！
Well, Kanata-chan has drunk it before,
もちろん当ててくださる…
so of course she will guess correctly...
しかもあれですよね？一緒に飲みましたからね！
Besides, we drank it together, right?
あの、いただきましたよね！
You know, you gave me some!
それ以外に日本酒全然飲んだことないから、どうなんだろうなぁ〜？
I've barely drunk any other sake besides that, so I wonder how this will go~?
予防線張るのやめてください！
Stop making excuses beforehand!
いやぁ〜どうなんだろう？
Man~ I wonder...
こちらは、外せば2ランクDOWNとなっております！
For this one, if you get it wrong, you drop 2 ranks!
それでは、かなたちゃん唯一ね、本日メンバーの中で雪夜月を飲んだことの…
Now then, Kanata-chan is the only member today who has drunk Yukiyozuki...
あるお方ですので、ぜひ当てていただきたいと思います！
so I really hope you can guess it right!
まず1番の日本酒から、どうぞ飲んでみてください！
First, please try drinking Sake Number 1!
ゴリレバのね、絆もありますから！
We have our GoriLeba bond, after all!
ゴリレバの絆、ここにあるかないかも分かってしまう！
This will reveal whether our GoriLeba bond really exists or not!
お酒の匂いがする！
It smells like alcohol!
浅いですねぇ…
How shallow...
お酒、いただきます！
Bottoms up on the sake!
目隠しをしていると…
When you're blindfolded...
やはり香りとか味とかっていうものはよく分からないと思うんですけれども、非常にフルーティーな気がしますね！
I think it's hard to tell the aroma and taste, but I feel like it's very fruity!
雪夜月はフルーティーだった覚えがありますから！
Because I remember Yukiyozuki being fruity!
それでは2番の日本酒、飲んでみてください！
Then please try drinking Sake Number 2!
どうでしょうか？
How is it?
わかったかも〜！！
I might have figured it out~!!
わかったかも、ということで、大丈夫ですか？2ランクダウンもあり得ますから！
You figured it out? Are you sure? Remember, you could drop 2 ranks!
も、もう1回1番をいただいてもいいですか？
C-Can I try Number 1 one more time?
す、すいません、すいません！
S-Sorry, sorry!
あ、もう分からなくなりました…
Ah, now I'm completely confused...
はい、ありがとうございます！それでは札の方を揚げていただきたいと思います！
Alright, thank you! Now please raise your sign!
雪夜月は 1番と 2番 どちらでしょうか？
Which one is Yukiyozuki, number 1 or number 2?
これは...
This is...
1番です！
Number 1!
お！これは何で 1番と思ったんでしょうか？
Oh! Why did you think it was number 1?
いやね、もうフルーティーさが違う。あと香りが...
Well, the fruitiness is just totally different. Also, the aroma...
1番が80匂ったとしたら...
If number 1 smelled like an 80...
2番は15くらいしか匂わず...
Number 2 only smelled like a 15...
1番のフルーティーさ、そしてあの香りの豊潤さ...
Number 1's fruitiness, and that rich aroma...
味の奥深さ、なんとなく甘く感じる雰囲気などなど...
The depth of flavor, the subtly sweet atmosphere, and so on...
美味しい！と。日本酒をまったく飲んだことがないかなたそでも美味しいと感じた！
Delicious! Even Kanataso, who has never drunk Japanese sake before, thought it was delicious!
こちらも美味しいですけど...
This one is delicious too, but...
語彙力がすごいですねぇ！
Your vocabulary is amazing!
でしょ？MCラミィ様との絆を優先し...
Right? Prioritizing my bond with MC Lamy-sama...
ありがとうー！ / 本気で答えます！
Thank you! / I'm answering in all seriousness!
これで1番じゃなかったら、本当「ゴリレバ」の絆はもうないということで...
If this isn't number 1, it means the "GoriLeva" bond is truly no more...
一切ありません！
Absolutely non-existent!
一切コラボがなくなると...
There will be no more collabs...
不仲になりますということで...
We will become estranged...
それでは1番のお部屋に行ってください！
In that case, please head to room number 1!
行ってきます！
Here I go!
はい、それではAZKiちゃん！
Alright, next up is AZKi-chan!
はい！
Yes!
えー、ラミィの作った雪夜月、当ててください！
Um, please guess which one is the Yukiyozuki made by Lamy!
実は初めて飲みます...！
Actually, this is my first time drinking it...!
ヒントをひとつ出すのであれば...
If I were to give you one hint...
雪夜月は、日本酒を飲んだ事がない方でも...
Yukiyozuki was designed so that even people who've never drunk sake...
美味しく飲める日本酒を目指して制作いたしましたので...
...can enjoy drinking it as delicious sake...
1番の日本酒から飲んでみてください。
Try tasting sake number 1 first.
飲まずとも香りとかでも違うと思いますので...
Even before drinking, I think the aroma alone will be different...
はい...
Right...
え〜、なんか結構辛い匂いがするな...
Huh... It has kind of a strong, dry alcohol scent...
多分ほんとに舌の上に一滴載せるぐらいでも全然...
Truly, even putting just a single drop on your tongue is plenty...
なるほど...？
I see...?
えぇ〜？
Eeh~?
これは飲みやすいと言うのか...？
Would you call this easy to drink...?
2番いただきます。
I'll try number 2.
えぇ〜？
Huh...?
AZKiちゃんは2ランクダウンしますと「他人の空似」になりますので...
If AZKi-chan drops 2 ranks down, you'll become "Total Strangers", so...
雪夜月 1番と 2番 どちらでしょうか？
Which one is Yukiyozuki, number 1 or number 2?
えー、日本酒初心者として飲みやすかったのは... 2番！
Um, as a Japanese sake beginner, the one that was easier to drink was... number 2!
2番ということで！
Number 2 it is!
理由としてはやはり...
And your reason for that is...?
いや、そう、なんかその飲みやすさっていうのと、普段飲まないので...
Well, yeah, the ease of drinking, plus since I don't usually drink...
これ出された時に飲みやすいのは2番だなあと！
...when served this, number 2 felt much easier to drink!
いやあ、今日は飲み物系が難しい...
Man, drink tests are so hard today...
いや、日本酒... 飲まないので...
Yeah, since I don't drink Japanese sake...
ちょっともう自信が限りなくないんですが...
I have virtually zero confidence, but...
2番の部屋に入ります。
I'll enter room number 2.
いてくれ...
Please be in here...
誰もいない...！
Nobody is here...!
かなたんがいない...
Kanatan isn't here...
唯一飲んだことがあるという... かなた〜ん！！
The only one who said she had drunk it before... Kanata~n!!
AZKiちゃん... 酔っぱらってる？？
AZKi-chan... are you drunk??
はい、それでは一流アイドル、ペコラ様！
Alright, next up is First-Class Idol Pekora-sama!
えー、ラミィの作った雪夜月、飲んでいただきたいと思います。
Um, I'd like you to taste the Yukiyozuki made by Lamy.
まずは1番の日本酒から。
First, starting with sake number 1.
まず匂いから。どうぞ、お願いいたします。
Starting with the scent. Go ahead, please.
なるほどなるほど... ラミィ...
I see, I see... Lamy...
どちらがよりラミィらしいかという点でもいいかもしれないですね。
Evaluating which one feels more like Lamy might be a good angle too.
あぁ、そういう感じでやればいいのか。
Ah, so that's the angle I should take.
じゃあちょっといただきます。
Then I'll take a sip.
う〜ん！うんうん...！
Mmm! Mm-hmm...!
大丈夫です。日本酒はまあ、はいはいはい...
Are you okay? Sake is indeed, yes yes yes...
じゃちょっといただきます。
Then I'll try number 2.
はいはいはい... わかりましたぁ。
Okay, okay, okay... I got it.
お！なるほど！飲み直しなしで回答ということで...
Oh! I see! Making your answer without a re-taste...
もう一度行ったら死んじゃうから。
Because if I taste again I'll die.
大丈夫でしょうか？
Are you sure you're ready?
はい、わかりました。 / それでは札を上げていただこうと思います。
Yes, I'm ready. / Alright, then please hold up your sign.
はい！ラミィが作った雪夜月は...
Yes! The Yukiyozuki made by Lamy is...
ドゥルルル... 1番！
*drumroll* Number 1!
1番ということで、こちら理由は？
Number 1 it is! And what is your reason?
ちょっと申し訳ないぺこなんですけど、ちょっと日本酒はそんな嗜んだことがなく... 分からなかったんですが！
I'm really sorry, peko, but I haven't really drank much sake... so I couldn't tell! But!
1番の方が...
Number 1...
なんかラミィちゃんっぽい香りというか... なんだろう...
...had more of a Lamy-like scent, or like... how to put it...
「ラミィ」だな... っていう。
...it felt like "Lamy"...
でも感想浅いですけど大丈夫ですか？w
But that's pretty shallow reasoning, are you sure? lol
マジで日本酒はちょっと分からない...
I really don't know sake...
頼む... でも誰かしらはいるんだろうな。
Please... But surely someone is in here.
いてくれよ！
Please be in here!
頼む！ / ぺこら様ぁあ〜！！
Please! / Pekora-samaaa~!!
飲んだことあるって言ってたよね！ / そうだよ！ / 私、雪夜月飲んだことありますからね！
You said you'd drunk it before, right! / That's right! / I've drunk Yukiyozuki before, after all!
またひとりだぁ...
Alone again...
大丈夫ぺこか？ww
Are you okay, peko? lol
はい、それでは空ちゃん！ / はい！
Alright, next up is Sora-chan! / Yes!
ラミィの作った雪夜月なんですが...
Regarding the Yukiyozuki that Lamy made...
まず1番の日本酒...
First, for Japanese sake number 1...
香りの方を ちょっと遠目からでも 手でこう扇ぐ感じで...
Let me fan the aroma towards me with my hand, even from a bit of a distance...
うん... なんか...
Yeah... it kind of...
柔らかい感じの匂い...
...has a soft kind of scent.
なるほど、柔らかい香り。
I see, a soft scent.
それでは次、2番の日本酒の香りを嗅いでいただきましょう！
Next, let's have you smell the sake for number 2!
あ、ん？
Ah, huh?
あ、なんかこっちの方が...
Ah, this one feels more...
なんだろう... さわやかな...
How should I put it... refreshing...
匂いがする気がします。
...I feel like it has a refreshing scent.
逆にね、これ香りだけで当てられたら本当にすごい。
Conversely, if you can guess it right by smell alone, that'd be amazing.
丸くてフルーティーなんですよね。
It's round and fruity, isn't it?
そうですね、角がない感じの日本酒になっております。
That's right, it's a sake that feels smooth and rounded.
わかりました！やってみます！
Got it! I'll give it a try!
はい、それでは札をあげていただきましょう！
All right then, please raise your paddle!
はい、それではそらちゃん！
Okay then, Sora-chan!
ラミィの作った雪夜月、1番と2番どちらでしょうか？
Which one is Lamy's Yukiyazuki, number 1 or number 2?
こっちかな？1番かな？
Maybe this one? Number 1?
1番ということで！
Going with number 1!
丸くて、あの、フルーティーっていう風に言ってくださったと思うんですけど...
You mentioned that it's round and fruity, but...
2番の方が、こう、さっきも言った通り、ちょっとツンとした「お酒」って感じの匂いがした気がして...
...like I said earlier, number 2 felt like it had that sharper, distinct "alcohol" smell...
で、やっぱり丸いってなるとツンとした感じも少ないのかなって思って1番にしました。
...and since "round" means less sharp, I chose number 1.
なるほど！
I see!
どうかな？どうかな？
How is it? How is it?
ドキドキだあ～！！
My heart is pounding!
いるかな？
Are they in here?
ん？間違えた！
Hm? My bad!
キャー！！
[Screaming in room 1]
もうだめだあ...
It's all over...
結果発表
[Title: Results Announcement]
さてさて...
Now then, now then...
ラミィの雪夜月、もちろん当ててくれたのは...
The one who got Lamy's Yukiyazuki right is, of course...
どっちだろう...？当てるのは...
Which one is it...? The one who guessed it is...
AZKi先輩ってことで！
AZKi-senpai!
イエーイ！
Yay!
よかったあー！！
Thank goodness!!
ラミィは感無量でございます！
Lamy is filled with deep emotion!
当たり前だろ！
Of course!
『ラミあず』始まる前に終了
[Title: "LamiAz" ended before it even started]
AZKi 2ランクDOWN
[Title: AZKi DOWN 2 RANKS]
どうしたって！ 消せない夢も 止まれない今も
No matter what! Dreams I can't erase, a present I can't stop,
誰かのために強くなれるなら
If I can become stronger for someone's sake,
ありがとう 悲しみよ
Thank you, sadness!
世界に打ちのめされて
Beaten down by the world,
はい、それでは雪夜月の問題が終わりましたが...
Alright then, now that the Yukiyazuki question is over...
なんか 他人の空似...？ AZKi先輩の他人の空似がいるらしい
Wait... a lookalike...? It seems AZKi-senpai's lookalike is here.
誰ぺこだあ？？
Who on earth are you, peko??
AZKiだよっ！
It's AZKi!
こんなあずきち（AZKi）なわけないじゃん！
There's no way Azukichi looks like this!
部外者がいるんですけど...
There's an intruder here...
困りましたね、しかも「ござ」だし...
That's problematic... and she's on a straw mat too...
※他人の空似には「ござ」をご用意
[Title: A straw mat was provided for the lookalike]
足痛っ...
My legs hurt...
隣がまた一流アイドルのオーラ...
Sitting next to an aura of a top-tier idol...
一流アイドルの隣に他人の空似を置かないてもらっていいですかぁ？
Could you please not put a lookalike next to a top-tier idol?
すいませんけど(笑)
Sorry to say, but (laughs)
ほんとですよ！
Seriously!
皆様は今... 次の問題も？？
Everyone is now... For the next question too??
2ランクDOWN
DOWN 2 RANKS
いやいやいや...
No, no, no...
次のジャンルはこちらでございます！
Here is the next category!
サイン
Signatures
サイン！？
Signatures!?
ということで、鷹嶺ルイのサインはどっち？当てていただきたいと思います！
So, which one is Takane Lui's signature? Please try to guess!
えぇー！？
Ehh!?
こっちだ！
It's over here!
やっぱこっちだよねぇ〜！
I knew it had to be this one~!
主役どこ行った？
Where did the star of the show go?
アアアアア...
Ahhhhh...
きっと空似になるでしょあの人
That person will definitely become a lookalike.
やだぁ〜！！ 主役ぞっ！
No way~! I'm the star of the show!
結果発表
[Title: Results Announcement]
これが分かんないヤツ... おるぅ〜？
Is there anyone who doesn't know this...? Anyone~?
おんなぁい！
There's no one!
イエーイ！
Yay!
こちら正解でございます！
This one is correct!
ぺこら様を信じろなのさ！
Trust in Pekora-sama!
見事に正解！ということで...
A magnificent correct answer! So...
あれ？ どこ行っちゃったんだろ？
Huh? Where did she go?
あれ？
Huh?
なんか...
Like...
なんかドアの隙間から見えてる気がする
I feel like I can see you through the gap in the door...
今からそっちに行っていいですか？
Can I come over there now?
ダメに決まってんだろっ！！
Of course you can't, dummy!!
はい！ということで...
Alright! So then...
なんか芸術的！
It looks kind of artistic!
令和のピカソ！
The Picasso of the Reiwa era!
すごい！
Amazing!
すごいじゃない... あんまそんな嬉しく...
Don't say it's amazing... I'm not that happy...
こちらの絵、「他人の空似」のかなたの絵は...
This picture, the drawing of Kanata in "Pretender" status...
某・戌神ころねが書かれた...
was drawn by a certain Inugami Korone...
なんか炎吐いてます？
Is she breathing fire?
なん... なんだろうこれ？
What... what is this?
輪郭どうなってんだろ？
What's going on with the outline?
天才だな、やっぱり
She's a genius after all.
これでグッズ出した方がいいんじゃない？
Shouldn't you sell merch with this?
いらねぇよ！！
I don't need that!!
ちなみに、かなた以外の「他人の空似」は...
By the way, the "Pretender" faces other than Kanata's...
スタッフの厳選なる落書きだそうです。
are carefully selected doodles from the staff.
ポイントは輪郭だそうです。
The key point was apparently the outline.
真面目に描いたみたいですよ。
It seems they drew it quite seriously.
真面目に描いてのこちらでございます。
This is what came out of drawing seriously.
絵を描かずに生きてきたのでしょうねぇ...
She must have lived life without ever drawing...
ということでね、ラスト問題になります！
So then, onto the last question!
おー！
Yay!
次のラスト問題...
The next and final question...
間違えると...
If you get it wrong...
最悪、即ドボンとなります！
At worst, you drop straight down!
今までのなんだったんだよ！！
What was the point of everything until now?!
一流アイドルのぺこら様も...
Even First-Rate Idol Pekora-sama...
即ドボンとなる可能性がございます！
...could drop instantly to the bottom!
普通アイドルのそらちゃんも即ドボンで消える可能性がございます！
Average Idol Sora-chan also risks dropping straight down into disappearance!
今までの何だったんだ！
What was all of that for then?!
「他人の空似」様も...
"Pretender" status members as well...
顔見えてるようで見てないようなもんなので、関係ないと思いますけど...w
...can barely be seen anyway, so it doesn't really matter for them... lol
なんでだよ！全然違うわ！！
Why?! That's completely wrong!!
最後の問題！こちらでございます！ドン！
The final question is right here! Don!
ジャンル6、牛肉！
Genre 6: Beef!
お肉〜！
Meat~!
皆さん、自信ありますよね？
Everyone, you have confidence, right?
4人全員一気にいきます！
All 4 of you will go at once!
分かりました！頑張るぞ〜！
Understood! Let's do our best~!
それでは、「牛肉」を当てていただきたいと思います...が！
Now then, I'd like you to identify the beef... but!
その前に、今皆様の目の前にあるお肉...
Before that, the meats currently in front of you...
まず一つは「牛肉」
First, one is "Beef".
そして「豚肉」
And "Pork".
そして...「ワニ肉」となっております！
And... "Alligator meat"!
ワニ〜！？
Alligator~?!
これは絶対当ててほしくないなと...
I really hope you don't pick this one...
まさか皆様がワニ肉を牛肉だなんて勘違いしないですよね？
Surely you won't mistake alligator meat for beef, right?
まぁね... そうですね...
Well... yeah...
なんか声に覇気がないんですけど大丈夫ですか？
You sound a bit unmotivated, are you alright?
ワニ初めて食べるから... どんな味なんだろ〜！
I've never eaten alligator before... I wonder what it tastes like~!
怖いよ...
I'm scared...
ということでね、まず1番のお肉から食べていただきましょう！
So then, let's have you try meat number 1 first!
いただきます
Bon appétit / Let us eat.
気をつけてくださいね。
Please be careful.
え、小っっちゃ...！
Huh, it's tiny...!
いかがでしょうか？皆様、どうですか？
How is it? Everyone, what do you think?
小っっちゃすぎてムズいな...
It's too small, so it's hard...
なんですか？ぺこら様。
What is it, Pekora-sama?
なんか肉ちっちゃくねぇ？って
I was like, "Isn't this piece of meat tiny?"
肉ちっちゃいなぁ...
The meat is tiny...
楽しみにしてたんだけど、とんでもねぇミニサイズなんだけど
I was looking forward to it, but it's such a ridiculously mini size...
ぺこら様ならお分かりになるんじゃないですか？
Wouldn't someone like you figure it out, Pekora-sama?
一流ですからね！
Because I'm first-rate!
それでは、2番のお肉も食べていただきましょう！
Now then, let me have you try meat number 2!
よく噛み締めて味わって食べてくださいね。
Chew thoroughly and savor the flavor, alright?
肉って全部同じに感じてきた...
All meat is starting to feel the same...
普通に美味しいんですけど、今のところ全部...
They're all pretty delicious so far...
変な味する？
Does it taste weird?
美味しい気がする！
I feel like it's delicious!
ワニって美味しいのかな？
Is alligator actually tasty?
残りはあと1つになっておりますが、皆様大丈夫ですか？
There's only 1 left, is everyone ready?
いただきます
Let me try it.
おー、でも頷いている方も！
Oh, but some of you are nodding!
分かっちゃった！
I figured it out!
かなたちゃんは分かったということでしょうか？
Does that mean Kanata-chan figured it out?
分かっちゃった！お肉は任せてくださいよぉ！
I figured it out! Leave meat questions to me!
みんな分かりました？
Did everyone figure it out?
え、もう1回貰っていい...？ - ないです！
Wait, can I get another bite...? - No you can't!
これだと思う番号を指と声で示していただけたらと思います！
Please indicate the number you think it is using your fingers and voice!
分かんねぇから好きな数字にするわ！
I don't know, so I'll just pick my favorite number!
ちなみに全種類当てたら（ランク）戻れたりとか... - あ、ないですね...
By the way, if we guess all of them right, can we return to our original rank...? - Ah, no you can't...
ないんかい！
Wait, what?! It's not even there!
なんだよっ！
What the heck!
皆さん、牛肉だと思われるのは何番でしょうか？
Everyone, which option do you think is the real beef?
せーの！
Ready, set...
3番！
Three!
えーっと、3番、3番、2番、3番ということですね。
So we have #3, #3, #2, and #3.
それでは！結果発表ー！
Now then! Time for the results!
この中に、即ドボンする方がいらっしゃいますね～！
Among you, someone is about to get instantly eliminated!
誰だー！？
Who is it?!
やだー！
Oh no!
来るなー！
Please don't be me!
せーの！
Ready... set...
あぁ～やってしまった～！
Ahhh, I messed up~!
そら先輩！
Sora-senpai!
どこ行ったぺこなの〜！？
Where did you go, peko~!?
私は空に飛んでったぞ〜！
I flew up into the sky~!
ときのそら 空に散る
Tokino Sora vanishes into the sky!
そらだけにね！
Because her name is Sora!
そら〜！
Sora~!
さようなら〜！
Goodbye~!
ありがとうございました〜！
Thank you so much~!
なんで死んだの〜！？
Why did she have to die?!
それでは皆さん、お疲れ様でした〜！
Well then, everyone, thank you for your hard work!
お疲れ様でした〜！
Thank you for your hard work!
それではね、改めて結果を振り返ってみようと思います。
Now then, let's review the final results once again.
まず、一流アイドルの兎田ぺこら様！
First, our First-Class Idol, Usada Pekora-sama!
どうも〜！やっぱり一流アイドルと言ったら、ホロライブ界のGACKTになろうかなと...
Hello~! Speaking of first-class idols, I was thinking of becoming the GACKT of Hololive...
ぺこら様でしたら大丈夫だと思います！
I'm sure you'll be completely fine, Pekora-sama!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
そして『他人の空似』のAZKi、かなたということで... かなた〜！
And then, as "Imposters", we have AZKi and Kanata... Kanata~!
はーい！
Yes~!
いや、僕もですね、今日主役でございましたし、一応ホロライブ界のGACKTというのを前は自分で言ってたんですけど...
Well, I was supposed to be the main star today, and I used to call myself the GACKT of Hololive...
もうやめてくださいね？
Please stop doing that, okay?
ぺこら様にお譲りしようかなと...
I guess I'll hand that title over to Pekora-sama!
非常に楽しかったですー！
It was a whole lot of fun!
そして『他人の空似』のAZKi！
And next, also as an "Imposter", AZKi!
はーい、AZKiですー！
Hi, it's AZKi!
みんなあの... 頑張ってAZKiの顔思い出してください！
Everyone, please try your best to remember what AZKi's real face looks like!
それではということで、以上3名でした...
So with that, those were our three participants...
あ、あらららら〜？声が聞こえる？
Oh? Huh? I hear a voice?
天の声です！
It's a voice from heaven!
天音かなたさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday, Amane Kanata-san!
ラミィさんも格付けをするということで、とても楽しみにしております！
Lamy-san will also be hosting a rating test, so I'm really looking forward to it!
楽しみに開発いたしますね！頑張ってくださいね！
I'm super excited for it! Please do your best!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ということでね、ここでお知らせがございます！
Alright, we have an important announcement right here!
本日、天音かなたが誕生日記念グッズを出されるということで...
Today, Amane Kanata is releasing her birthday commemorative merchandise...
その顔で言うことなんですか？
Are you really going to present it with that face?
せっかくなんで紹介します？
Well, since we're here, why don't we introduce them?
お願いしてもよろしくでしょうか？
Would you mind doing the honor for us?
はい！今回出すグッズはこちらー！
Yes! Here is the merch lineup for this release!
はい！ということで天音かなた誕生日記念グッズ2023、この後22時から発売されますー！
So, Amane Kanata Birthday Commemorative Merch 2023 goes on sale tonight at 22:00!
これさ、2分以内に納めなきゃいけないんだけどさ、もう4回目なんだけど全然2分超えるんだが... 難しい！
I have to fit this into 2 minutes, but this is my 4th try and I keep going over! It's so hard!
誕生日記念フルセットはこちらでございます！ドドンと！
Here is the Birthday Commemorative Full Set! Ta-da!
こちらのフルセットは5種類ついてきますよ！
This full set comes with 5 awesome items!
フルセット購入特典、数量限定バージョンの方は... なんと直筆サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードが入っております！
The limited edition full set bonus includes a hand-signed cheki-style bromide card!
ぜひぜひゲットしてください！
Be sure to grab yours!
そしてグッズの方はB2タペストリーとなっております！イラストはDSマイル先生！かっこよく歌を歌ってライブ会場にいるようなかなたでございます！
Next, for the merch, we have a B2 tapestry illustrated by DS Mile-sensei! It captures Kanata singing coolly as if on stage!
そしてランダムラバーストラップはこちら！みんな大好きもちみこ先生の可愛い可愛いとけそうなほっぺついたイラストになっております！
And here is the random rubber strap! It features super cute art by Mochimiko-sensei with squishy cheeks everyone loves!
全4種類ゲットいただけたらと思います！そして前回大好評だったデジタルシングルがCD化！
Get all 4 types! Also, we have physical CD releases of my digital singles!
3rd Single『中空の庭』！こちらのジャケットはrurudo先生、アシマ先生が書いてくださっております！
3rd Single "Chuukuu no Niwa"! Jacket artwork is by rurudo-sensei and Ashima-sensei!
そして毎回恒例の特典音源！かなたのソロカバーも収録されております！ぜひゲットしてください！
And as usual, it includes a bonus cover track sung solo by Kanata! Please check it out!
そして次！4th Single『別世界』！こちら作詞作曲かなたの...
Next up, 4th Single "Bessekai"! Written and composed by Kanata...
なんとですね
Believe it or not,
こちらの楽曲
for this song,
ジャケットはオリジナルキャラクターであったのでございますが
the jacket originally featured the original character, but...
今回 せっかくグッズ化ということで
since it's being turned into merchandise this time,
MVのキャラクターデザインを担当してくださった津田先生に
Tsuda-sensei, who designed the MV characters,
かなたそデザインのジャケットを描き下ろしていただきました！
drew a new jacket featuring Kanata's design!
そしてこの「別世界」のロゴを作ってくださった
And Tamano Hazuki-sensei, who created
玉野ハズキ先生にもですね
the logo for "Bekusekai",
なんとデザインをしていただきました！
also designed it for us!
こちらのジャケット等々 本当にすごいことになっておりますので ぜひチェックしてください！
This jacket and everything turned out really amazing, so please check it out!
そして こちらの撮り下ろし音源は全曲で歌わせていただいております！
And I sang all the songs on this newly recorded audio source!
「Over Time」もかなたソロでやっておりますので ぜひ聴いてください！
"Over Time" is also a solo track by me, so please listen to it!
あ ちょっと2分オーバーしたけど 大丈夫だよね？「Over Time」ってことで！それでは！
Ah, I went 2 minutes over, but it's fine, right? Because it's "Over Time"! Now then!
はい ということでね 今回CD 2枚出させていただくんですけれども グッズとして
Alright, so we're releasing two CDs as merchandise this time.
その「別世界」の方 描き下ろしのジャケットが今回ありますので…
For "Bekusekai", we have a newly drawn jacket illustration...
そら！そら持ってきて そら！
Sora! Sora, bring it over here, Sora!
あー そらありがとね！そらありがと！これになっておりますのでね
Ah, Sora, thank you! Thank you, Sora! It looks like this...
描き下ろしていただきました「別世界」のかなたそのジャケットですよ！
It's a newly drawn jacket illustration of Kanata for "Bekusekai"!
可愛い！きれい！
So cute! So pretty!
あれ？空仙が見えないな… 空仙が見えないぺこですよ！
Huh? I can't see Kuusen... You can't see Kuusen-peko!
まあ ここにね 美しいかなたが… こっちの方が本物のかなたに近いんですね
Well, here is the beautiful Kanata... This one is closer to the real Kanata.
はい こんな感じでCDも出ますので ぜひ皆さん…
Yes, so the CD will be released like this, so everyone...
よろしくお願いします！ お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Please check it out! Happy Birthday!
お誕生日おめでとー！
Happy Birthday!
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!
はい 1番！
Okay, number 1!
はい 2番！
Okay, number 2!
どうですか？
How is it?
それでは 正解は…
Now then, the correct answer is...
2番！
Number 2!
正解です！
It's correct!
いや ラミィね 正直ね あの…育ちがいい… 次行きましょうか！
Honestly, Lamy comes from a good... Let's move on to the next one!
これはいち… 1番！
This is... number 1!
何？正解！
What? Correct!
これが1だよー
This is number 1.
はい 分かりました え もういいの？ 2番！
Yes, I got it. Eh, already? Number 2!
正解ー！ もうね 分かるのよ 香りから分かる！
Correct! I can just tell from the aroma!
雪夜月当ててくださいよー
Please guess Yukiyazuki correctly~
はい 一口ね ゴクゴク
Okay. One sip, gulp gulp.
うん あ うま！
Mmm. Ah, delicious!
1番！ 1番！ 正解ー！
Number 1! Number 1! Correct!
ありがとうございます！ここで間違えてたら次の雪夜月 ちょっと発売なしに…
Thank you very much! If I had gotten it wrong here, the next release of Yukiyazuki might have been...
はい これ1番 はい 1番ね
Okay, this is number 1. Yes, number 1.
評価してくださいよ これ全部当ててほしいな
Please evaluate it. I hope you get all of them right.
オッケー 牛肉は何番でしたでしょうか？ 2番！
Okay. Which number was the beef? Number 2!
正解ー！ 全問正解で じゃあ可能性ある…
Correct! With all answers correct, then there's a possibility...
じゃん！豚 3番！
Ta-da! Pork, number 3!
正解ー！ すげー！全問正解じゃん！
Correct! Amazing! You got every single one right!
一流空仙だからこそのMCだったっていう結論付けができたってことですね！
We've reached the conclusion that it was an MC performance worthy of a first-class Kuusen!
結果的には ぶっちゃけすごい！
Result-wise, to be honest, it's amazing!
ありがとうございました！雪花ラミィでございました！
Thank you very much! This was Yukihana Lamy!